GUOWEI (Peter) LU

peter6.lu@gmail.com • Github • DoB: 1983

PROFILE

I am a PhD student at the Computer Graphics and Visualization group under the supervision of Prof. Elmar Eisemann. My research focuses primarily on real-time rendering, realistic material, and lighting models. In addition, I am interested in in offline/differentiable rendering. Before this, I was a 3D GIS engineer in China working on the development of virtual earth.

EMPLOYMENT

PhD student, CGV Group, TU Delft, the Netherlands

June 2022 - Now

 VR Renovate Project: The goal of this project is to research and test effective real-time graphics and visualization technology based on virtual reality displays, intended to provide an accurate depiction and understanding of the results of sustainable home renovations.

Architect/Engineer, R&D Department, SuperMap, Beijing/Chengdu, China

Jul. 2006 – May 2022

- 3D GIS: I am working on real-time rendering and WebGL, striving to constantly improve the visual quality and performance. My responsibilities include spatial 3D model specifications (terrain, oblique photography, point cloud, BIM. etc.), LOD scheduling, rendering (PBR material, shadow, post processing etc.), and GPU/CPU optimization.
- Map Module: I worked on the map module, including styled vector, text rendering, anti-aliasing, and cross-platform capability (Windows, Linux, Android, Unix).

EDUCATION

Utrecht University, the Netherlands

Sep. 2018 - Sep. 2020

M.Sc. in Computer Science, Game and Media Technology

- Courses: Advanced Graphics, Optimization and Vectorization, Game Physics, Computer Vision, Geometric Algorithm, Motion and Manipulation, Crowd Simulation, and Scientific perspective
- Master Thesis: 'Gradient-Domain Volume Rendering' (grade: 8.5/10)
- GPA: 8.73/10

Beijing Forestry University, China

Sep. 2002 - Jun. 2006

B.Sc. in Information Management & Information System

PROJECTS

SBDPT • C++, CUDA • 2019

A streaming bidirectional path tracing rendering system. #Optix, wavefront.

Fluid Simulation • C++, Compute shader • 2019

Position Based Fluid Simulation. #collision, rigid body, clothes.

Action Recognition • Python, Keras, tensorflow • 2019

A CNN architecture to classify human actions **#Stanford-40 dataset**, data augmentation, transfer learning.

Cesium tutorial(Chinese) & Demos • JS, WebGL • 2017

Cesium tutorials written in Chinese and a gallery of Cesium demos. #MapBox vector tile, height map terrain, dynamic data visualization.





ACHIEVEMENTS

Graduation with Cum Laude	2020
Innovation Award (Company, team)	2016/2008
National High School Mathematics League, National 3 rd prize, Provincial 1 st prize	2001
A Method of 3D Line of Simple Geographical Elements (Patent ZL2012103648 40.7)	2017
Data format for spatial 3D model (Social Organization Standard T/ CAGIS 1—2019)	2021

MISCELLANEOUS

Programming Language
Oral & Written

C++, JS, Python, CUDA, WebGL
English(medium, IELTS 7), Mandarin(Native)

^{*}For all projects, please visit my <u>project portfolio</u>.